Guide to the Emil J. Dillon Papers, ca. 1873-1933
Department of Special Collections
- Series 3. Subjects and Events, 9 linear ft.
  - Subseries 4. Countries and Regions
    - Albania [3 of 6]1912[?] June 23 - 1915[?] Dec.[?] 12[?] (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Albania [4 of 6]1914 May 20 - June 20 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Albania [5 of 6]1919 Apr. 22; incl. undated materials (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Albania [6 of 6]1919 Oct. 10 - 1922 Feb. 11; incl. undated materials (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - America [1 of 4]1894[?] Sept. 22 - 1921 July 16; incl. undated materials (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Includes press cutting. Refers to: Cyrus H.K. Curtis; Hughes; Senator Walsh; Mr. Daugherty; Mr. Wells Note: one press cutting is in German.
    - America [2 of 4]1921 Nov. 9 - Nov. 16 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - America [3 of 4]1922 July 4 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - America [4 of 4]1922 Nov. 25 - 1923 Jan. 17 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Armenia [1 of 17]1894[?] - 1895; undated/dates are illegible (Box 9, Folder 12)
      Includes: press cuttings,.letters, als, telegrams, notes music sheet, a descriptive list, a newspaper, a score, typescripts, manuscripts, a ticket, viziting cards, accounts, clippings. Refers to: Le Sage; Pulszky; Abgar; R.W. Graves; Minas Tcheraz; I. Souzanadzhian; Bunting; George C. Cope; Boghos Nubar Pasha; Nubar Pasha; Lord Cromer; Lord Milner; Aharonian; Pasdermadjain; Pres. Wilson; Mr. Gkadstone; Canon M'Coll; The Bishop of Chester; Lord Kenyon. Note: some materials are in Armenian, Russian, and French.
    - Armenia [2 of 17] 1895; undated/dates are illegible (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Armenia [4 of 17]1895 April 16/28 - May 1 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Armenia [5 of 17]1895 May 10 - May 23; incl. undated materials (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Armenia [6 of 17]1895 May 23 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Armenia [7 of 17]1895 May 23 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Armenia [8 of 17]1895 May 23 - July 12 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Armenia [9 of 17]1895 July - Aug. 7 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Armenia [10 of 17]1895 Aug. 7 - Nov. 24 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Armenia [11 of 17]1895 Dec. 9 - 1896[?] Feb. 20 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Armenia [12 of 17]1896 March 3 - 1918 Dec. 31 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Armenia [13 of 17]1919 May 9 - 1932 Aug. 12; incl. undated materials (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Armenia [14 of 17]Undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Armenia [15 of 17]Undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Armenia [16 of 17]Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Armenia [17 of 17]Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Armenia [2a of 4]1909 - 1910 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Armenia [3a of 4]1913 Feb. 27 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Armenia [4a of 4]Undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
      Note: in Armenian.
    - Austria [1 of 3]1892 Apr. 21 - 19[10/11?]; incl. undated materials (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Includes: notes, typescripts, press cuttings, a letter, tls. Refers to: Franz Ferdinand; Count Berchtold; Aerhrenthal; Signor Tommasini; Izvolskii; Russell; Douglas; Szapary; Crozier; Clemenceau; Poincare; the King of Montenegro; Buchanau; Chops; Sir Arthur Nicolson; Tyrrell; Countess Berchtold; Countess Lonyay; Comte Hubert Harnincourt; The E mperor; Count Lutzow; Dr. Baernreither; Professor Redlich; Dr. Friedjung; Dr. von Grabmayr; Crow; Director Spitzmuller; Baron Goschen; Ferdinand of Bulgaria; Giers; Prince Kudasheff; Sir Edward Grey; Bashmakoff; Dutchess d'Uzes; Ashinoff; Cartwright; Tagblatt; Steed; Yantshevetzkii; Du Maine; Kokofftseff; Baron Motono. Note: some materials are in German.
    - Austria [2 of 3]1913 Feb. 24 - May 13 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Austria [3 of 3]1914[n.d.] - 1920 Apr. 27; incl. undated materials (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Belgium [1 of 2]1918 Apr. 18 - Dec. 18 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      Includes: notes, letters, an offprint, a typescript. Refers to: Leopold II, the King of Belgium; King Albert; Baron Beyens; Hanotaux. Note: one letter is in French.
    - Belgium [2 of 2]1919 Feb. 17[?]; incl. undated/no year materials (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Brazil1921 Dec. 3 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      Includes a press cutting. Note: in French.
    - Britain [1 of 7]1885 - 1911 Apr. 4; incl. undated materials (Box 10, Folder 16)
      Includes an offprint, typescript Refers to: Dr. Albert Berzeviezy[?]; Harry Cust; Lord Robert Cecil; Winston Churchill; Lord French[?]; Lord Burnham; King Edward VII; Mr. Lloyd George; Lord Lansdowne; Lord Roseberry[?].
    - Britain [2 of 7]1910[? - 1911; incl. undated materials (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Britain [3 of 7]1911; incl. undated materials (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Britain [4 of 7]1913 Feb.[?] - 1916 Jan. 23; incl. undated materials (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Britain [5 of 7]1917 May 9[?] - May 24; incl. undated materials (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Britain [6 of 7][No year] July 31 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Britain [7 of 7]Undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Bulgaria [1 of 7]1915[?] July 22 - 1918 Jan. 17; incl. undated materials (Box 10, Folder 23)
      Includes: an offprint, typescripts, notes, statistical data, press cuttimgs a clipping. Refers to: King Ferdinand; Grand Duke Vladimir; Stambuloff; Petroff; Kaiser Franz Josef; Lamsdorff; Goluchowskii; Kaza Osman Effendi. Note: some materials are in French.
    - Bulgaria [2 of 7]1918 Sept. 30 - Oct. 1; incl. undated materials (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Bulgaria [3 of 7]Undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Bulgaria [4 of 7]Undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Bulgaria [5 of 7]Undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Bulgaria [6 of 7]Undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Bulgaria [7a of 7]Undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Bulgaria [7b of 7]Undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Bulgaria [7c of 7]Undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Central America1922 May 26 - May 29 (Box 10, Folder 32)
      Includes press cuttings. Note: in Spanish.
    - China [1 of 17]1896 May 22 - 1904 Jan. 27 (Box 10, Folder 33)
      Includes: descriptive lists, press cuttings, letters, tls, manuscripts, typescripts, notes, offprints. Refers to: Sun Yat Sen; Yuan Shi Kai; Motono; Yang[?] Yu Wei; Sir Robert Hart; Lobanow; Witte; Pelham Warren; Hsu Shu-tseng; Chang Tso-lin; Mr. Dixon; Selfridges; H.L.W. Clark; Forbes, E.W.; Dora Fox; Mrs. Fulham. Note: some materials are in German, Russian, French, and Japanese.
    - China [2 of 17]1898 - 1902 [n.d.] (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - China [3 of 17]1900 July 23 - Aug. 27; incl. undated materials (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - China [4 of 17]1900 [?] [n. d.] (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - China [5 of 17]1900 [?] [n. d.] - 1901 Jan. [n.d.] (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - China [6 of 17]1901 Jan. - March 22 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - China [7 of 17]1910 June 28/July 11 - 1911 May 2 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - China [8 of 17]1911 Apr. 20 - 1912 July 30 Aug. 12 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - China [9 of 17]1913 Jan. [n.d.] (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - China [10 of 17]1913 Jan. 11 - 1930 June 25 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - China [11 of 17]1916 June 23 - 1920 May 9 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - China [12 of 17]1920 June [n.d.] - 1924 Dec. 17 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - China [13 of 17]1925 June 7 - 1926 Feb. 5; incl. undated materials (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - China [14 of 17]1925 June 21 - Oct. 5; incl. undated materials (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - China [15 of 17]Undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - China [16 of 17]Undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - China [17 of 17]Undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Cuba1922 Apr. 24 - Apr. 28 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      Includes press cuttings Note: in Spanish.
    - Finland [1 of 2]1891 Jan. 6/8 - Jan. 13/25; incl. undated materials (Box 11, Folder 18)
      Includes: notes, press cuttings, a letter, a bussiness card, a program, invitations. Note: some materials are in Finnish, Russian, and Swedish[?].
    - Finland [2 of 2]1891 Jan. 6/18 - 1910 May 7; incl. undated materials (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - France [1 of 8]1891 Jan. 6/18 - 1910 May 7; incl. undated materials (Box 11, Folder 20)
      Includes: notes, typescripts, press cuttings, notes, a letter. Refers to: Paul Deschanel; King Edward VII; Mr. Lloyd George; Mr. Pams; Gen. Ferry; Sir Artur Paget; Miss Weiss; Contesse de Montebello; Alexeieff; M. Louis; Bompard; Tardieu; M. Poincare; M. Caillaux; Marshal Mac Mahon; M. Loubet; M. Grevy; Izvolskii; Dreyfus; M. Meline; the Tsar. Note: some materials are in French, Russian, German, and Spanish.
    - France [2 of 8]1899 June 19 - 1909 July 5 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - France [3 of 8]1911 May 11 - 1922 Nov. 15 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - France [4 of 8]1915 Nov. 1; incl. undated materials (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - France [5 of 8]1916 Aug. 11 - 1919 March 29 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - France [6 of 8]1925 Sept. 5 - Oct. 28; incl. undated materials (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - France [7 of 8]1927 May 12; incl. undated materials (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - France [8 of 8]Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Germany [1 of 8]1901 Oct. 25 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Includes: notes, typescripts, press cuttings, an offprint. Refers to: Napoleon III; Bismarck; Von Bulow; the Kaiser Wilhelm II; Admiral von Tirpitz; Paul Lanoir; Emilio de Hanos; President Roosevelt; Alexander III; Springr Rice; Sir Edward Grey; Benckendorff; the Sultan of Turkey; Musurus Pasha; Witte; Count Nesselrode; Count Pozzo di Borgo; Tatishcheff; Count Moltke; Prince Baritinskii; Prof. Carl Schmitt; S. Fischer. Note: some materials are in French, German, and Russian.
    - Germany [2 of 8]1904 Dec. 6 - 1914 [n.d.] (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Germany [3 of 8]1914 Oct. 17[?]; incl. undated materials (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Germany [4 of 8]1918 Nov. 10 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Germany [5 of 8]1932 July [n.d.] - Nov. 4 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Germany [6 of 8]Undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Germany [7 of 8]Undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Germany [8b of 8]Undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Germany [8c of 8]Undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Germany [8d of 8]Undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Germany [8e of 8]Undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Germany [8f of 8]Undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Greece [1 of 10]1897 June 22/July 4 - 1909 Oct. 6/18; incl. undated materials (Box 12, Folder 16)
      Includes: notes, typescripts, press cuttings, an offprint, manuscripts, als,tls, descriptive lists, photocopies of various materials, a letter, telegrams, viziting cards, statistical tables. Refers to: Venizelos; Dr. C.M. Foumis; King George; King Conctantine; M. Mitzakis;Mr. Streit;Triantaphyllides; Gennadios; Romanos; Stratos; Theodokis; Rhallis; Typaldos; Tricoupi; Colonel Tsorbas; A. Kyron; Gen. Vassos; Mallet[?]; Talaat Bey; Le Sage; Mavromichalis; Essad Pasha; the Tsar; Miliukoff. Note: some materials are in French, Greek, and Italian.
    - Greece [2 of 10][1910?] Apr. 27 - May [13/30?]; incl. undated materials (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Greece [3 of 10]1910 Aug. 7 - 1912 [n.d.] (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Greece [4 of 10]1915 Dec. 12 - 1916 Sept. 27; incl. undated materials (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Greece [5 of 10]1917 March 19 - 1931 Dec. 27 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Greece [6 of 10]Undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Greece [7 of 10]Undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Greece [9a of 10]1909 Oct. 13 - Oct. 30 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Greece [9b of 10]1909 Oct. 16; incl. undated materials (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Greece [9c of 10]1909 Oct. 16 - Nov. 4 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Greece [9d of 10]1909 Oct. 19 - Nov. 18 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Greece [9e of 10]1909 Nov.[?] 2/15 - Dec. 7/20 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Greece [9f of 10]1909 Dec.[?] 20 - dec. 8/21; incl. undated materials/date is illegible (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Greece [9g of 10]1917 Jan. [n.d.] (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Greece [9h of 10]1909 [n.d.]; incl. undated materials (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Greece [10a of 10]1914 June 17 - July 2 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Greece [10b of 10]1914 July 9 - July 14 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Greece [10c of 10]1914 July 15 - July 25; imcl. undated materials (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Greece [10d of 10]Undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Greece [10f of 10]1914 July 15 - July 16; incl. no date/ no year materials (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Greenland 1903 Feb. 1 (Box 13, Folder 15)
      A press cutting. Note: in German.
    - Haiti1921 May 9 - Aug. 4 (Box 13, Folder 16)
      Press cuttings. Refers to: Mr. Villard; Mr. Colby; Rear Admiral Mayo; Rear Admiral Knapp; Secretary Daniels; Dr. F. Henriquez.
    - Hungary1912[?] [n.d.]; incl. no year materials (Box 13, Folder 17)
      Includes notes, a typescript. Refers to: Baron Macchio.
    - Italy [1 of 9]1911 May 22 - 1914 Apr. 3/19; incl. undated materials (Box 13, Folder 18)
      Includes: notes, typescripts, manuscripts, letters, tls. Refers to: Nesti; Giolitti; Sonnino; Chiaraviglio; Salandra; Martini;Barere; The French Ambassador; Volpi; M. Orlando; Bianchi; Boselli; Rehnel Roold; Theodoli; Fasciott; Fiamingo; Tommasini; Ivolskii; Aehrenthal; King Edward; Tittoni; Kaiser. Note: some materials are in Italian.
    - Italy [2 of 9]1915 Feb. 23 - Apr. 26 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Italy [3 of 9]1915 Dec. 6 - 1916 Oct. [n.d.]; incl. undated materials (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Italy [4 of 9]1916 Nov. 5 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Italy [5 of 9]1916 Nov. 6 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Italy [6 of 9]1916 Nov. 7 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Italy [7 of 9]1916 Nov. 8 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Italy [8 of 9]1917 Apr. [n.d.] - 1922 May [?] 18; incl. no year materials (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Italy [9 of 9]Undated (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Latin America1922 Apr. 6 (Box 13, Folder 27)
      Includes a press cutting.. Note: in German.
    - Mexico [1 of 10]1920 Jan. 31 - Aug. 19 (Box 13, Folder 28)
      Includes: notes, tls, telegrams, letters, als, a manuscript. Refers to: Campeche[?], Lamont; President Obregon; Cummins; Wiseman; W.B. Johnson; J.B. Body; Prof. D. Alfonso L. Herrera; Carrranza; De La Huerta; Kathleen Dillon. Note:some materials are in Spanish.
    - Mexico [2 of 10]1920 Feb. 12 - 1925[?] Feb. 26 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Mexico [3 of 10]1920 Aug. 13 - Sept. 23 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Mexico [4 of 10]1920 Nov. [n.d.] - 1921 Aug. 3 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Mexico [5 of 10]1922 Apr. 12 - Apr. 26 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Mexico [6 of 10]1923 March 19 - Oct. 15; incl. undated materials (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Mexico [7 of 10]Undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Mexico [8 of 10]Undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Mexico [9 of 10]Undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Mexico [10 of 10]Undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Mexico [1a of 3]1921 May 5 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Mexico [2a of 3]1922 Feb. 25 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Mexico [3a of 3]1925 Feb. 24 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Mongolia1912 Nov. 2 (Box 14, Folder 10)
      A press cutting. Refers to: M. Korostovetz; Khutukhta; Yuan-Shi-Kai.
    - Morocco1905-1910 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      Refers to:the German Emperor; Herr von Kuhlman; the Kaiser; Count von Bulow; Count von Tallebach.
    - Persia1922 July 27 - 1925 Dec. 21 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      Press cuttings. Refers to: Aga Khan; Shah Fateh Ali; Riza Shah; Shah Abbas the Great; Mussolinni. Note: some materials are in German and Spanish.
    - Poland [1 of 6]1902 March [n.d.] (Box 14, Folder 13)
      Includes: press cuttings, notes, typescripts, manuscripts. Refers to:Count Josef Potocki; Raffalovitch; Mr. Reutinger[?]; Prince Worobetsky; Peater[?]; Dmoffsky; Lord Miluer; Balfour; George Clark; Robert Cecil; Count Plater; Tsar Nicholas II; Maklakoff; Wielopolsky[?]; Pilsudski; Paderewsky. Note: some materials are in German and French.
    - Poland [2a of 6]1916 Dec. 2 - Dec. 6 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Poland [2b of 6]1917 Feb. 10 - March 24 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Poland [2c of 6]1917 Apr. 4 - Apr. 14 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Poland [3 of 6]1917 Feb. 5 - Feb. 9; incl. undated materials (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Poland [4 of 6]1918 Apr. 9 - 1921 Oct. 8; incl. undated materials (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Poland [5 of 6]Undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Poland [6 of 6]Undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - PortugalUndated (Box 14, Folder 21)
      Notes. Refers to: King Manuel of Portugal.
    - Roumania [1 of 4]1913 Jan. 9 - Feb. 6 (Box 14, Folder 22)
      Includes: telegrams, tls, press cuttings, notes, a letter, a typescript. Refers to: Mishu; Ferdinand of Roumania; Cormeanu[?]; Take Jonescu; King Carol; Maiorescu. Note: some materials are in French and Roumanian[?].
    - Roumania [2 of 4]1913 May 21[?] - 1916 Jan. 31 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Roumania [3 of 4]1916 Nov. 10 -1917 May 18 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Roumania [4a of 4]1913 July 7 - July 13 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Roumania [4b of 4]1914 Nov. 21 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Roumania [4c of 4]1915 Jan. 29 - 1917 Aug. 27 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Roumania [4d of 4]Undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Russia [1 of 19]1894 Feb. 18 - Sept. 13; incl. undated materials (Box 14, Folder 29)
      Includes: typescripts, tls, an offprint, descriptive lists, press cuttings, notes, a letter, a leaflet, a manuscript. Refers to: Miliukoff; Maklakoff; Alexeieff; Bezobrazoff; Izvolskii; the Tsar Nicholas II; Raffailovich; Azeff; Loppukhin; Stolypin; Gapon; Witte; Fedoroff; Iollos; Plehve; Pobedonostseff; Gen. Trepoff; Burtzeff; Vera Figner; Rachkovskii; Stalin; Trotskii; Thomas G. Masaryk; Muravieff; the Kaiser; Rasputin; Rakovskii; Motono; Hofmann; Arnold Rechberg; Sturmer; Protopopoff. Note: some materials are in German, French and Russian.
    - Russia [2a of 19]1905 Jan. 12/25 - Dec. 8 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Russia [2b of 19]1906 July 24; incl. undated materials (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Russia [2c of 19]1917 July [n.d.] (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Russia [2d of 19]Undated (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Russia [3 of 19]1908 June 6 - Aug. 2/15; incl. undated materials (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Russia [4a of 19]1909 Jan. 16 - Jan. 22/Feb. 4 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Russia [4b of 19]1909 Jan. 22/Feb. 4 - June 5/18 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Russia [4c of 19]1909 Jan. 25/Feb. 7[?] - May 2/15 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Russia [5 of 19]1909 [n.d.] - 1910 June 21/July 4 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Russia [6 of 19]1910 July 20 - 1916 Dec. 8; incl. undated materials (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Russia [7 of 19]1917 March 22 - Apr. 21 (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Russia [8 of 19]1917 June 8 - 1919 Aug. 22; incl. undated materials (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Russia [9 of 19]1918 Feb. 9- May 5 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Russia [10 of 19]1919 May 25 - Nov. 26 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Russia [11a of 19]1920 July 11; incl. undated materials (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Russia [11b of 19]Undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Russia [11c of 19]Undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Russia [12 of 19]1921 Nov. 21 - 1924 May 31; incl. undated materials (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Russia [13 of 19]1928 [n.d.] - 1930 Dec. 20 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Russia [14 of 19]1931 May 2 - Sept. 11 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Russia [15 of 19]Undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Russia [16 of 19]Undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Russia [17 of 19][No year] Jan.10 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Russia [18 of 19]Undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Russia [19 of 19]Undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Russia - Communism, Marxism, Bolshevism1927 June 16 - 1932 Feb. 14 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      Typescripts. Refers to: Antonio; Lenin; Wrangel; Denikin; Montaner.
    - Russia - Tsar [1 of 8]1901 Sept. 19 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      Includes: notes, press cuttings, tls, offprints, a letter, als[?], a typescript. Refers to: the Kaiser; the Tsaritsa Alexandra Fedorovna; Sir Arthur Nichilson; Gen. Botha; Fisher; Prothero; Count Kokovtsoff; Sazonoff, Rasputin; Alexander II; Alexander III; M. Pobedonostseff; Witte; Plehve; L.J. Maxse, Esq.; Mr. Leveson Cower. Note: some materials are in Russian.
    - Russia - Tsar [2 of 8]1904 June 13 - July [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Russia - Tsar [3 of 8]1904 July 28 - 1905 Jan. 30; incl. undated materials (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Russia - Tsar [4 of 8]1905 Oct. 28 - 1918 June 22 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Russia - Tsar [5 of 8]1918 Aug. 1 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Russia - Tsar [6 of 8]1918 Sept.; incl. undated materials (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Russia - Tsar [7 of 8] Undated/a date is illegible (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Russia - Tsar [8 of 8] Undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Servia1902 Jan. 25 - 1907 Sept. 22 (Box 15, Folder 24)
      Press cuttings Refers to: Queen Draga; Queen Natalie; King Alexander; the Russian Czar. Note: some materials are in German.
    - Spain [1 of 13]1898 Apr. 4 - July 31; incl. undated materials (Box 15, Folder 25)
      Includes: press cuttings, notes, typescripts, descriptive lists, a letter, an offprint, a blocknote, diary extracts. Refers to: Alfonso XIII; Sanchez Guerra; Miguel Primo De Rivera; Marques de Estella; Count Castellane; M. Sert. Note: some materials are in French and Spaniah.
    - Spain [2 of 13]1898 May 5 - 1902 Aug. 13; incl. no date/ no year materials (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Spain [3 of 13]1904-1909 [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Spain [4 of 13]1906 Dec. 2 - 1910 Nov. 13 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Spain [5 of 13]1913[?] March [n.d.] - 1917 Oct. [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Spain [6 of 13]1917 Oct. 8 - 1918 March[?] 1 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Spain [7 of 13]1932 July [n.d.]; incl. undated materials (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Spain [8 of 13]Undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Spain [9 of 13]Undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Spain [10 of 13]Undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Spain [11 of 13]No date/no year materials (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Spain [12 of 13]Undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Spain [13 of 13]Undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Sweden [1 of 5]1914 Apr. 4 - 1915 May 10 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      Includes: notes, typescripts, a descriptive list, a memorandum. Refers to: Mr. Howard; M. Wallenberg; Karl Staaff; Dr. Key; M. Khylberger; Dr. Eklund; M. Waltz; Dr. Markoff; Mr. Goerge S. Hein; Axel Ahrberg; Mr. Buckley; Charles XII; Nansen; Madame Adam; Nekhliudoff, Russian Minister; Branting; King Gustav; Lindmaun; Trolle; Westmann; Hamarskjold.
    - Sweden [2 of 5]1916 March 1 - March 13 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Sweden [3 of 5]1916 March 15 - March 21; incl. no year materials (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Sweden [4 of 5]1916 March 23 - March 27; incl. undated materials (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Sweden [5 of 5]Undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Turkey [1 of 15]1908 Feb. 17 (Box 16, Folder 13)
      Includes: notes, typescripts, a descriptive list, tls, an offprint, press cuttings, telegrams, letters, a manuscript. Refers to: Colonel Sadik Bey; Talaat Bey; Hilmi Pasha; Mr. O'Mahony; Robert Thomson; Abdul Hamid; Cheriff Pasha; Nazim Bey; Prince Abdul Medjid Effendi; Count Ostororog; Enver Bey; Boustany; Sazonoff; Turhan Pasha; Count Witte; Assim Bey; Mr. Lawson; Baron Marschall von Bieberstein; the Kaiser; Prince Sabah[?] Eddine; the Sultan of Turkey. Note: some materials are in French and Spanish.
    - Turkey [2 of 15]1908 Sept. 18/Oct. 1 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Turkey [3 of 15]1908 Nov. 3; incl. undated materials (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Turkey [4 of 15]1911 Oct. 16 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Turkey [5 of 15]1911 Oct. 30 - Nov. 2 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Turkey [6 of 15]1911 Dec. 2 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Turkey [7 of 15]1912 Feb. [n.d.] (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Turkey [8 of 15]1912 March 18/31 - May 5/18 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Turkey [9 of 15]1912 Sept. 29 - 1926 Sept. 4 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Turkey [10 of 15]Undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Turkey [11 of 15]Undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Turkey [12 of 15]Undated (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Turkey [13 of 15]Undated (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Turkey [14 of 15]Undated (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Turkey [15 of 15]Undated/no year (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Subseries 5. Miscellaneous Materials
    - Miscellaneous Materials [1 of 27]1899 Oct. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [2 of 27]Undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [3 of 27]Undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [4 of 27]Undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [5 of 27]Undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [6 of 27]Undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
      Note: in Russian.